■ eslaaam.fawzy@gmail.com

geophysicist_es1

**** 01125669737

♀ Cairo, Egypt

in eslamfawzv96/

geoeslamfawzy

Skills

MANUAL TESTING

Test Case Writing

Bug Reporting

SRS Writing

TEST AUTOMATION

Selenium Grid

TestCafé

Appium

Cucumber

Allure Reporting

PERFORMANCE TESTING

Jmeter

API TESTING

Postman

REST Assured

CONFIGURATION MANAGEMENTNT

GIT

Jenkins

DATABASE DEVELOPMENT

MySQL

SQL Server

AGILE METHODOLOGIES

Scrum

Kanban

XP

WEB TECHNOLOGIES

HTML

CSS

Javascript

XML

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Java

С

C++ C#

Python

LINGUISTIC SKILLS

English

Arabic

ESLAM FAWZY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER IN TEST

Self-Learning Software Testing Engineer with excellent communication, and interpersonal skills, proven team player with an analytical mind leads to problem-solving and delivering solutions. Build and Develop automated tests using various specialized tools and different programming languages. Searching for a challenging role in a reputable organization that offers immense growth opportunities to implement my advanced knowledge and skills to contribute to the success of the organization.

Education

9-Month Professional Diploma Of Software Testing and Quality Assurance

Oct. 2021 -Current

Information Technology Institute (ITI) – Smart Village Egypt

Bachelor Degree Of Science

Oct. 2014 - June 2018

Ain-Shams University, Cairo, Egypt Cumulative Grade: - Very good (81%)

Work Experience

GeoEnergy Petroleum Service [EUG Project Team]

Zahraa ElMaadi, Cairo Feb. 2020 - Apr. 2022

Senior Geophysicist
Responsible for wells and seismic data transcription and integration

IBA, AAPG

Junior Geophysicist

Intern Geophysicist

Jan. 2019 - May 2019

Seismic and well data interpretation for basin analysis and modeling Petroleum system analysis, prospect generation, and evaluation Creating a 1D basin model using Petromode software

British Petroleum (bp)

New Cairo, Egypt June 2017 - Aug. 2017

Seismic and well data interpretation for basin analysis and modeling of QWASIM formation at the eastern part of Nile Delta

Projects

Build Test Framework from Scratch

Designed with POM Pattern, supports multiple browsers, using data-driven to read from a Properties file, JSON file, CSV file, and XLSX, reporting using Allure and taking a screenshot, build on Jenkins integrated with GitHub, run the framework using XML, support BDD using Cucumber, and run with Selenium Grid.

Online Car Booking Website

End to end Project that includes all development life cycle phases, that includes

- Formal Customer Requirements Gathering with (SIQ, SRS) documents
- Project Planning, Analysis, and Documentation with (PMP, WBS) documents
- High and Low-Level System Design with (Use Cases, Flow Charts, Sequence Diagram, ERD, Wireframe)
- Software Implementation using PHP, MySQL, HTML, and CSS
- Manual Testing For the whole system and Bug Reporting documentation
- Configuration Management Plan, (RTM), and Configuration Management Using Git and GitHub.

Guru99 Banking Project

Reviewing SRS, writing tests and bug reports, Testcases design and execution

Paintbrush Program

Desktop Java Application using Applets and Threads

Petroleum Website Static Page

Build Static Web Page for a petroleum service company using HTML5 and CSS3

Certifications

ISTQB Certified AI Tester Foundation Level	Candidate
ISTQB Certified Mobile Tester	Apr. 2022
ISTQB Certified Agile Tester	Apr. 2022
ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level	Mar. 2022
Awards	
Ranked Fourth over World in IBA 2019 · AAPG	May 2019

African Region Champion in IBA 2019.AAPG

Mar. 2019

Lagos, Nigeria

Winning First Paper Award at EGS Students Forum · Egyptian Geophysics Society

Mar. 2017

EGS Conference 2017

San Antonio, Texas, USA

Online Courses

Test Automation University

Automating your API tests with REST Assured Selenium WebDriver with Java Techniques Continuous Integration with Jenkins Scaling Tests with Docker

Cucumber with Java

Selenium 4 in Java

Source Control for Test Automation with Git

Web Element Locator Strategies - Introduction to Software Testing Concepts & Techniques Introduction to TestNG

MaharaTech

Introduction to Software Testing
ISTQB Foundation level
Effective Test Case and Bug Report Writing
Database Fundamentals

LinkedIn

Test Automation Foundation Advanced Jmeter

Volunteering

SPWLA - ASUSC · Cofounder and Former President Society of Petrophysics and Well Logging Analysts – Ain Shams	Apr. 2015 - Oct. 2018
Science Sea Rovers · Scout Boy Ain Shams University	Oct. 2015 - May 2017
Goal Human Development Academy · Former Project Manager	Dec. 2016 - Oct. 2017
Konna Zayak Initiative · Public Relation Specialist	Aug. 2016 - Nov. 2019